Big trouble, Kimaki!
And Sir Thundering Voice's party!
The Guren Nairi that attacked
yesterday is still outside, waiting!
For warriors and knights like us...
Fighting on the front line...
is where we are most powerful!
Have the others back down!
Miss Sera!
The backup hunters are in position.
Tell our comrades not to
worry about friendly fire.
The pressure of this willpower...
It's coming!
The Warrior Princess and the Barbaric King
No follow up attack...
it's sizing me up.
How very shrewd, for a dragon.
Veor must've neutralized
its flame breath!
No. It's still got a slight edge!
If it wasn't for the Silver Flower,
I would've at least been injured.
Sera!
I won't guess at what it's after,
but coming to ground is an opportunity
for us! We need to attack!
You're right. If it goes airborne
again, we'll be at a disadvantage.
So hard! The pressure from its
willpower is unlike anything else!
My own willpower channeled through
my weapon is nearly neutralized!
Sera!
Let's bring it down, Sera!
It's got a typical quadruped's agility!
Even the gaps between its
scales don't feel vulnerable.
This is likely to turn into a
battle of willpower attrition!
Master Veor...
Lady Serafina...
They're struggling!
I-Is that thing really on the level of
the Morisuberi they hunted the other day?
I-I don't know how you expect me to know!
I-If I only I had my scripture...
I see. Looks like it's time
to put that into action!
I had a feeling it'd come to
this, so I stayed up late...
making this chain detonation dragon bomb!
Dwarf girl! I won't have you blowing
them up along with the beast!
The flash grenade from the other
day barely had any effect!
And remember what she said
about friendly fire?!
Be that as it may, there are limits!
I get the feeling you just
want to test this contraption!
Put it down!
Well, I have to throw it now!
Look out! I'm tossing a bomb!
Seven... six...
Five... four...
Three... two...
One!
Did it work?!
Master Veor!
Lady Serafina!
Stands to reason the blast
wouldn't have much effect
with no willpower behind it.
I knew that was gonna happen,
but still don't like the result!
It's looking this way!
Not good, not good!
We're toast!
Well done!
You let me catch my breath, Kimaki!
It's stunned!
The pressure is gone!
I must strike now!
It was able to defend!
Did it realize the battle was
lost if I reached its head?!
Sera!
I'm sorry, Veor. I couldn't finish it!
Not good... It's in the air.
Veor!
Between my armor and my voice,
that won't be enough to kill me.
You can't be unharmed after being
blasted with willpower-enhanced flames!
I can withstand it better than
you can in that steel armor!
You rang, and I came, Red!
I haven't heard from you in an age!
Lady Vyufmec?!
Lady Vyufmec...
What's the fairy doing here?
I couldn't tell you, either.
Lady Vyufmec... when you said
you were called, do you mean...?
You guessed it!
Red here wants to talk with you
and Illdoren, so he summoned me.
That was a splendid blow you struck.
Was that... the dragon talking?
It has been many an age since anyone
was able to do any harm to me.
He's even got a distinct voice!
You heard 'em, Red.
We are all creatures of great will.
How can it be strange that we're
able to converse using it?
Yeah, I'm with him on that one!
I mean, my kin are just
wind and water incarnate,
and we can talk just fine...
Red here's got a will of
his own, like a person.
Why wouldn't he be able to communicate?
Though it's less talking,
and more like me translating his dragon
will, and then interpreting it as sound.
I-I see...?
For as long as I've known you,
this is a true first.
Well, I've tested you like I intended to.
I'm returning home.
What, already?! I thought
we were gonna chat more!
H-Hold it!
Begging your pardon, fire dragon,
but what do you mean by a test?
You can't just attack
us out of the blue,
and then suddenly
decide you're satisfied!
Fair enough.
Vessel of Orkfiem, and Illdoren...
Having endured my test, you have proven
yourselves worthy of speaking to.
Though my wound does ache,
so I intend on being brief.
Uh... right. My apologies.
Why apologize?
I sought to test your power,
which you demonstrated.
This wound is that very proof.
You should be proud.
If I had intended on killing you,
I would've endlessly rained
flame upon you from upon high.
And if I had no intent on testing you,
why would I ever enter
the range of your claws?
A dragon just poked holes in my logic!
No matter. On to the point.
I tested you for a simple reason.
Illdoren, after a long absence,
has finally returned to our territory.
As such, it is the custom of
dragons to test one another,
with fang, claw, and will.
Illdoren... returned?
In what way has my homeland returned here?
Your homeland...?
Then the name has fallen
into the hands of a pack...
I'm afraid there's little more
I have to tell you, then.
You're unlikely to remember
much more until you've seen,
heard, and felt more of
these lands yourself.
We're done talking.
I am returning—
Forgive me, but I would ask one
last question of you! Please.
What is it now, vessel of Orkfiem?
Fire dragon, my people had no idea
you true dragons were so wise
and capable of exchanging will...
Just the other day, the people of my
village hunted a Morisuberi unto death.
Having spoken with you,
that now feels like a grave misdeed.
Fire dragon, I would ask your
judgment on the matter!
Morisu...? What are you talking about?
Red, red, those mori-things are the
black ones. I've seen 'em before.
Oh, he means the black ones, Vyufmec?
One of their mighty number has
been felled? I see, I see.
Vessel of Orkfiem...
The one you hunted was likely
large and long-lived,
ruling over the forests, using its
amazing strength to tear its foes apart,
with strength comparable to ours.
If one so mighty was slain by
ones as small as yourselves,
it could only be because...
It was senile.
Senile as in... the loss of faculty
that some experience with age?
If you understand what I meant,
then I'm certain that was the case.
I don't understand your surprise.
We are living creatures as well.
We decline and grow ill, just like you.
All life passes in time, much like
all rainfall eventually ceases,
and the sun must eventually set.
The loss of faculty for those of
us who have risen up by our will
is an acceptance of a gradual death.
And in our fading years,
we are defeated, killed,
and serve as sustenance for new life.
I see no reason to deny that natural law.
Natural law...
Indeed. Natural law.
You suggest treating us differently
because we can communicate...
but we, you, the beasts, the plants,
all are equal lives
in the face of natural law.
Natural law is the great flow of life
itself, stretching through all of time.
And if all who live make up
a portion of its waters,
as long as it remains unadulterated,
we dwell within natural law.
Besides, had you failed my test,
I would've devoured you and all
the smaller folk around you.
You need feel no restraint when
dealing with me or the black ones.
A-As eloquent as he is, the logic
undermining it all is so... bestial.
Granted, he is a beast...
I take it I've answered
your questions, then?
Well, it had better be.
I wish to return home.
My hand hurts far more than I would
like. I will go back and sleep.
Orkfiem's vessel and Illdoren...
If the mood strikes me, once I've
healed, I may pay you a visit.
I'm not sure that's a good idea...
It was a joke.
Farewell, vessel of Orkfiem and Illdoren!
When we next meet, I hope you'll
have an offspring to show me.
Ow!
I think I might cry...
Bye-bye! And I'm out, too!
True dragons are more
garrulous than I expected.
I had no idea the Guren Nairi could talk.
And what did he mean about
an offspring at the end?
As long as it remains unadulterated,
all life dwells within natural law...
What is it, Veor?
I was just pondering how,
should we have a child,
that would be another
part of the flow of life.
We have done nothing
to conceive a child yet!
Don't get ahead of yourself, fool!
R-Right you are. Forgive me.
We... We certainly have not yet, no.
Why are you acting embarrassed, now?!
Master Veor!
Lady Serafina!
Lady Serafina! I'm so glad you're alive!
You're not hurt, are you?
Malcius! I'm sorry to have worried you.
I was so very seriously worried!
Understandably so.
It seems we were spared
thanks to the fire dragon being
reasonable, in its own way.
Though if he was an ordinary beast,
we would've likely won without a struggle.
You could've also been seriously hurt
if the dragon had felt like it!
They spoke with the Guren Nairi!
Cornem warriors are amazing!
How much willpower do you
need to cut a dragon?!
Crystal Helmet, can we keep
the Guren Nairi's digit?!
What a day! We need to celebrate!
I have to say...
Given everything that happened on this
journey, I'm glad no one was lost.
Now then, Kimaki...
your mobile furnace, your tools,
your compressed fuel...
along with slabs of
True Silver for repairs.
Remember to channel willpower
through both your tools
and the True Silver when you
work, like I taught you.
I will, Grandpa.
You know, my dear Kimaki...
Our people live a long time,
but even I, who've been around
for two centuries and change,
had no idea that fire dragons could speak.
The Thundering Voice and
the Crystal Helmet...
I'm sure that, if you follow them,
you're bound to see amazing things.
Work hard, and never forget the
pride of your people, Kimaki.
May good fortune and curiosity
light the furnace of your heart...
So that the flame will never go out.
Your friends look ready to go, as well.
Go on, Kimaki, my sweet grandchild.
Okay...
I'm off, Grandpa!
Next time I see you, we'll share
stories of what I've seen over drinks!
Be seeing you!
Take care!
Are you done with your goodbyes, Kimaki?
Sure am. It's not like I'm
never coming back, after all.
I'll need to pick up
supplies from time to time.
Looks like we're all ready.
Off we go, then.
We're flying!
It's now been over a month since
I started living in the east.
It's been such a short time,
but so much has happened.
All of it has been so strange,
defying what seemed like
common sense in the west...
Maybe if I convey what I've seen well,
it can lead to a future without fighting.
Veor...
What is it, Sera?
I've thought a great deal, and have come
to a conclusion I believe is right.
I've expanded my horizons,
and realized what I want...
Translation: Lee Francis
Timing: Andy Ellis
Editing: Zachary Carlysle
Quality Control: Salem Alabanza
Translation Check: Sho Stifler
It's to put an end to my expedition,
which began from a prejudiced
point of view...
I want to convey to my people
that exchange will be far more
productive than conquest.
I see.
And... I will officially resign
from my post as a knight...
After which... I will... marry you.
I see!
That's... a conclusion that
I couldn't be happier about!
Is something funny?
It's just...
I'm just a bit surprised about...
how much I seem to...
love you.
Sera...!
Please don't look at me like
that while saying such things.
Or do you enjoy testing my self-control?
That wasn't my intent...
entirely.
Sera!
m 10 0 l 210 0 l 220 10 l 220 65 l 210 75 l 210 75 l 10 75 l 0 65 l 0 10
Kingdom of Illdoren
Royal Capital of Le d'Illdoren
This now concludes my final report
on the 17th Expedition.
Margrave Sidius Lavillant...
You have my thanks for your
report on the expedition.
Guards?
Sir!
Give us some privacy.
I wish to discuss personal
matters with Margrave Lavillant.
I ask you...
Why was the expedition recalled when
we still had strength to spare?
m 10 0 l 210 0 l 220 10 l 220 85 l 210 95 l 210 95 l 10 95 l 0 85 l 0 10
King of Illdoren
Ouisselbreaux
d'Illdoren
Begging your pardon, my king...
Launching the 17th expedition a mere
thirteen years after the 16th...
Such a short interval leaves the
people with little time to recover.
And what of it?
You should know better than to believe
this campaign is meant
to serve the people.
My orders for you have always
been the same, Lavillant...
To seek out the barbarians who stole
my beloved sister, Wysteresia,
and tear them out by the roots!
That is your family's duty!
I even named your sister a
knight commander, to that end...
But it seems, for all her strength
of arms, she's still a woman.
Dying without accomplishing her mission,
may she be shamed in death.
It is nearly time for the harvest,
so I will grant you this short reprieve.
You are to re-organize the military
and begin the 18th
expedition by next spring.
This, I command.
Are you still entranced by the
spectre of the dead, my king?
Because of your fixation
on your late sister,
the expeditions... and my sister...
Regardless of my own desires,
I must attend to the
duty assigned to my house.
Ours has served
the country since its founding.
As head of the Lavillants, as I must
serve as the royal family's blade.
That will have to suffice, for now.
The Eastern Expeditions will
end with my generation.
I will exterminate the barbarians!